# **Dario Alessio**

#### FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Country: Denmark | Phone: +45-50 35 23 97 | Email | GitHub | Linkedin | Portfolio |

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with solid teamwork and communication skills developed through real-world project experience as a product manager/owner. Prone to learning new technologies and languages, and to use them for problem-solving and reaching the company's goals. With a degree in Mechanical Engineering and an MBA that helps to understand systems and businesses in general, beyond the language or technology used to model them.

### **SKILLS**

- Front-end: JavaScript, React, Rails, Redux, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Hotwire, Stimulus
- Back-end: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, API, Sidekiq, Pg\_search, RSpec, Capybara, OpenAPI (Swagger)
- Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, BDD, TDD, Unit testing, System testing, Chrome Dev, Kanban, Trello, User stories, Product backlog, Excel, MS Office
- Professional: Remote pair programming, Teamwork, Collaboration, Lifelong learner, Time management, Mentoring, Communication, fluent in Spanish, English & Italian

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# I-Spire Enterprises LTD Full-stack Ruby on Rails Developer

March 2023 – Present Remote

Full-time Developer for I-Spire Enterprises LTD, a software company based in Trinidad & Tobago. Primary responsibilities are backend and frontend development for commercial web apps for the company's clients. Achievements:

- <u>Dental Clinic App project</u>: Developed a graphical interface and backend for patients' dental charts (It lets the dentist create the patient's dental chart with a tablet, storing each tooth's value in the database). Also developed the full set of system testing with RSpec and Capybara. Applied skills: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Hotwire, Stimulus, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, API, Sidekiq, Pg\_search, RSpec, Capybara, OpenAPI (Swagger)
- <u>Digital Marketplace App project</u>: Developed the products search engine, the Admin Dashboard, the views and phone interactions statistical charts set for each product/user, several Sidekiq jobs, the automatic offensive words filtering, the feature for automatic filtering of undesirable text from uploaded images, the share on social networks feature, the Business Account feature, the product complaint feature, and several other features and most of the frontend. Applied skills: JavaScript, Rails, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Hotwire, Stimulus, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, API, Sidekiq, Pg\_search, RSpec, Capybara, OpenAPI (Swagger), Tesseract, etc.
- Created and approved more than 100 pull requests for the company's projects in 2023

# Freelancer Full-stack Web Developer

April 2022 – March 2023

Remote

Developed several projects both independently and via pair programming using JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, JS, HTML, CSS, Rspec, OpenApi(Swagger), Jest, Github, Kanban, Trello. The following are some examples of developed projects:

- <u>Plancha 1 CRC</u> landing page app to promote a group of club shareholders running for the Board of Directors election (commercial project) <u>Live demo</u> <u>Repo link</u>
- Astronomical Picture of the Day App for consuming and showing the daily updated NASA's API info (personal project) <u>Live demo</u> <u>Repo link</u>
- Space Travelers' Hub App for booking fictional rocket trips and space missions (academic project). <u>Live demo</u> -

Awesome Books — App for helping users keep track of books they have to read (academic project) - <u>Live demo</u> -

#### **MERCANTIL SERVICIOS FINANCIEROS**

Feb 1992-May 2020, Caracas, Venezuela

#### Mortgage & Auto Credit Manager

- Kept the bank's #1 position in the mortgage business in the country (circa 10% market share)
- Managed more than 12 improvement projects on the mortgage product

# **Auto Insurance Underwriter Manager**

Launched the first web portal for buying auto insurance in the country

# **Investments & Budget Manager**

• Managed the valuation and budget control on 40+ companies of the whole investment branch

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor in Mechanical Engineering**

Venezuela

UNIVERSIDAD DE ORIENTE (Link)

• Thesis: Designed and built a Hydraulic Ram Pump

MBA Venezuela

Instituto de Estudios Superiores en Administración (IESA) (link)

Awards: Awarded with the Heinz Award for Best Marketing graduate

Full-stack Web Developer Online

MICROVERSE (link)

• International program for HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, PostgreSQL, Github, Kanban, pair programming, etc.